Guide to City University of New York Catalogs, etc. Cubb.00287
Cubberley Education Library
City University of New York
1858-1977
Cubberley Education Library
Cubb.00287
378 item(s)
Located in New York City. University system of senior colleges, community colleges and graduate programs. The oldest was founded in 1847 as The Free Academy. Notes under the various colleges for more details.
New York (State)
- Brooklyn College, 1931-1973; 42 item(s) Men's Division Fall 1931 Bulletins for 1932/33-1944/45, 1946/47-1948/49, 1950/51-1955/56, 1957/58-1970/71 Undergraduate programs 1972/73
  - Report of the President, 1942-1966; 10 item(s) Reports for 1942/47-1951/53, 1961/63
    - Brooklyn College and self evaluation--a challenge to complacency, July, 1957; 1 item(s); Introductory chapter of the Biennial Report of the President of Brooklyn College...for the years 1955-1957.
    - Brooklyn College and the "Disadvantaged", 1966; 1 item(s); A chapter from the Biennial Report of the President of Brooklyn College...for the years 1963-1965.
  - Graduate Studies, 1945-1973; 8 item(s) Bulletins for 1945/46, 1948/49-1949/50, 1960/62, 1963/64, 1972/73 Master of Arts, Master of Arts in Education Spring term 1950
  - The Pointer, 1961-1962; 1 item(s)
  - Descriptive titles of courses and number of weekly hours, September 1932 - August 1954, 1 item(s)
- Bernard M. Baruch College (formerly Bernard M. Baruch School of Business and Public Administration of the City College), 1968-1977; 5 item(s) Graduate Division catalogs for 1968/69-1969/70, 1972/73-1973/74 Undergraduate catalog for 1976/77
- Bronx Community College, 1972-1976; 2 item(s) Catalogs for 1972/73, 1975/76
- City College of the City University of New York (formerly City College of New York, formerly College of the City of New York, formerly Free Academy of the City of New York), 1858-1973; 162 item(s); Located in New York City. Founded in 1847 as the Free Academy of the City of New York. In 1866 became the College of the City of New York and in 1929 became the City College of New York (CCNY). In 1961 became the City College of the City University of New York.
  - Free Academy of the City of New York, 1858-1866; 11 item(s) Registers for 1858/59-1863/64, 1865/66
    - Annual reports, 1861-1864; 4 item(s) Reports for 1861-1864
  - College of the City of New York, 1866-1933; 98 item(s) Bound with Free Academy registers for 1866/67-1868/69 Bound together registers for: 1869/70-1873/74 Bound together registers for: 1873/74-1874/75, 1876/77-1886/87 Bound together registers for: 1888/89-1898/99 Registers for: 1901/02-1903/04, 1907/08, 1910/11-1918/19, 1920/21-1928/29 Announcement of courses for 1916/17-1917/18, 1920/21
    - School of Education, 1921-1933; 6 item(s) Announcements for 1921, 1923-1924, 1930, 1933 Spring bulletin for 1925
    - City College Quarterly, 1906-1917; 34 item(s) Vol. 2, #2-3; vol. 3, #4; vol 4, #2-4; vol. 5, #1-2, 4; vol. 6, #1, vol. 7, #3-4; vol. 8, #1-4; vol. 9, #1-4, vol. 10, #1-4; vol 11, #1-3; vol. 12, #1-4; vol. 13, #1-3
    - The inauguration of Frederick Bertrand Robinson as fifth president of The College of the City of New York, 1928; 1 item(s)
  - City College of New York, 1929-1961; 31 item(s) Register for 1929/30-1933/34 Catalogs for 1934/35-1936/37, 1938/39-1942/43, 1946/47, 1950/51-1951/52, 1954/55-1959/60
    - Bernard M. Baruch School of Business and Public Administration (later Bernard M. Baruch College), 1958-1961; 3 item(s) Bulletins for 1958/59, 1960/61 Evening and Extension Division class schedule for Spring 1958
      Business schools
    - College of Liberal Arts and Science, 1948-1949; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1948/49
    - The inauguration of Harry Noble Wright as the sixth president of the City College, 1942; 1 item(s)
    - Year of dedication, 1955-1956; 1 item(s) Report for 1955/56
    - Summer session, 1957; 1 item(s)
    - Report of Harry N. Wright, President, 1941-1952, 1 item(s)
    - Report of the President, 1952-1954; 1 item(s) Report for 1952/54
    - Guide to elective courses according to educational and vocational interests and objectives, 1949-1950; 1 item(s) Guide for 1949/50
  - Bernard M. Baruch School of Business and Public Administration (later Bernard M. Baruch College), 1961-1967; 5 item(s) Bulletins for 1961/62, 1963/64-1966/67
  - College of Liberal Arts and Science, 1961-1973; 16 item(s) Graduate bulletins for 1961/62-1971/72 Undergraduate bulletins for 1960/61-1961/62, 1964/65-1965/66, 1972/73
  - School of Engineering and Architecture, 1964-1967; 3 item(s) Bulletins for 1964/65-1966/67
  - Problems and prospects of an urban public university: a report by Robert E. Marshak, President, 1970-1972; 1 item(s) Report for 1970/72
- Hunter College, 1914-1975; 134 Linear Feet Catalogs for 1914/15, 1916/17-1947/48, 1951/52, 1955/56, 1957/58-1960/61, 1962/63, 1964/65-1965/66; Located in New York City. Founded in 1870 as Female Normal and High School, chartered in 1888. Name changed to Hunter College in 1914. Became coeducational in 1951. Became part of the City University of New York in 1961.
  Women's colleges -- United States; New York (State); Teachers colleges
  - School of General Studies (formerly Evening and Extension Sessions), 1926-1967; 54 item(s) Sept. 1950-Jan. 1951, Sept. 1952-Jan. 1953, Sept. 1955-Sept. 1956, Sept. 1957-Fall 1958, Fall 1960-1966/67
    - Evening and extension sessions, 1926-1950; 36 item(s) Bulletins for 1926-Spr. 1939, Spr. 1940, Spr. 1941-Jan. 1946, 1947, Jan. 1948, 1949 Poster for Spr. 1950
  - Graduate Programs, 1960-1975; 7 item(s) Catalogs for 1960/61, 1962/63, 1964/65, 1966/67-1967/68, 1972/73, 1974/75
  - Summer Session, 1920-1961; 32 item(s) Bulletins for 1920, 1924-1925, 1931-1933, 1935-1943, 1945-1948, 1950-1952, 1954-1961 Poster for 1935 Information leaflet June 1950-1951
- Queens College, 1960-1974; 8 item(s) School of General Studies Bulletin for 1960/61 College of Liberal Arts and Sciences Bulletins for 1963/64-1964/65, 1966/67; Located in Queens, NY. Founded in 1937 as Queens College of the City of New York. Became part of the City University of New York in 1961.
  - Graduate Division, 1966-1974; 3 item(s) Bulletins for 1966/67, 1971/72-1972/74
  - Summer session, 1963; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1963
- University Graduate Programs, 1962-1977; 15 item(s) Bulletins for 1962/63-1976/77
  - Freshman Program Graduate Center, 1967-1968; 1 item(s) Information for 1967/68
- Report of the Chairman of the Board of Higher Education, 1948-1957; 4 item(s) Reports for 1948/50-1955/57
- Borough of Manhattan Community College, 1975-1976; 1 item(s)
  Community colleges
- New York City Community College, 1965-1974; 3 item(s) Catalogs for 1965/66-1966/67, 1973/74
- LaGuardia Community College, 1975-1976; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1975/76